We are going to be discussing about Microsoft Intune.
You know, Microsoft Intune is a cloud-based employee management solutions.
Its managed users are safe and simplifies apps on desktop, malignments across your many devices,
including mobile devices, desktop computers, laptops are virtual and point.
Intune is designed as a cloud service that is utterly meant to deliver two different things.
On the one side, it is utterly for mobile device, malignments and on the other side, we have
a mobile application on malignments.
So the cloud service deliver two different things, start as a mobile device, malignments
which is the MDM and the MAM which is a mobile application on malignments.
So in this video, I'll be focusing more on the mobile device malignments.
So when you think of Intune, there are two things that will come to your mind, the MDM and the MAM.
So when we are talking about the mobile device malignments, we are focusing on the 5th configuration
that could include the 5th application.
The primary focus of MDM as it contrasts with mobile application malignments is the fact
that we have some capacity to view inventory, make changes, first differ configuration on
device itself, most of our focus on this training would definitely be on MDM and not MAM.
And also Intune, MAM has integrated Microsoft 365 which allows it to integrate with Azure
Active Directory and Azure Information Protection.
So this will allow you to configure some rules that protect and manage your devices.
So in accomplishing all these roles and configuration in Microsoft Intune, it has about
six different categories that perform all the different activities.
First of all, we have the role device which of course when you want to enroll your device
in Microsoft Intune, definitely we can enroll personnel or conference devices.
We can't configure and control the files.
We can actually make sure that we configure how the users use the other files, which policies
should be applied to that device.
What should you do?
What should the users be able to do?
Which rules?
And also we can also protect the device by for example, want to make sure that the user
should not be able to use the device if an antivirus is not installed on that device.
Also, we have the deploy software to the devices with me that if for example, you want to deploy
company apps to your devices, or you want to deploy software to your mobile devices, or
your laptop or desktop that belongs to users, incorporates or even personnel device.
We can also deploy software to the devices.
We can also call in in February and report about that device.
So we can actually see the laws on the device.
We can see with software is installed on what and if for example, the device gets lost,
we can decide to wipe all the information from that device.
So you have to different approach on how you deal with Microsoft Intune.
The first one is 100% Intune, which means that you can manage all your company devices
using only Intune.
So Intune will be used for deploy software, policies and configuration.
Or we also have called core management, which of course you want to use config manager
and Microsoft Intune hand in hands.
So when you are using configuration manager, it means you will use but the config manager
and Intune to manage your company device.
For example, you can use config manager to deploy software to the devices while you use
Intune to apply configuration policies like firewall rules.
So you can either configure, under reset, Intune or go manage with config manager.